Finding Aid for the Yoneo Sakai Papers LSC.1426
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Materials
  - Cartilla escolar antifascist, 1937. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Maps, traveler's guide, etc., n.d. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Romancero gitano, etc., n.d. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Indonesia (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Indonesia (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Life World Library: The Arab, 1962. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition, Japanese painting, 1953. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Perspective of Japan: an atlas, 1954. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Perspective of India: an atlas, 1953. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Hungary's fight for freedom, 1956. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Spanish Civil War newspapers, 1937. (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Maps, telephone directory, etc., Dai 65-gun haibi yozu (1945, August 15), Hijoyo denwa (1943), Mexico and Central America, Atlantic Ocean, Burma, Thailand, Indochina and Malayan Federation. (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Spain, 1937.; Servicio de prensa, Delegacion del Estado para Prensa y Propaganda, Gabinete Civil de la 2a, Division Organica, etc. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Kawanari, Yo, 1979.; Includes correspondence and copies of articles by Kawanari. (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Press release, 1949-1978.; Department of Defense, Department of State, Joint Communique of Japanese Prime Minister Kishi and U.S. President Eisenhower (1960), The U.S. News Washington Letter (1978), etc. (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Japanese peace treaty, 1951.; Japanese peace treaty and other treaties relating to security in the Pacific. (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Ogasawara to Ryukyu shoto joken tsuki de henkan (Tokyo Shimbun, 1951, April 8), 1963-1977.; Includes Tokyo shimbun, Yomiuri shimbun, Mainichi shimbun, Ogon no California, etc. (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - The crucial years/ The 1960s - the 1970s, 1969-1974. (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Nichibei kyodo seimei, 1961.; Administrative arrangements for the arrival at Washington of His Excellency Hayato Ikeda, Prime Minister of Japan. (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Arms control and disarmament, 1963. (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Manned space flights, 1972. (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - New study sees Hirohito as a militarist (The New York Times, 1971, September 13), 1964-1978. (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Who was to blame for Pearl Harbor? (Parade, 1966, December 4), 1959-1977. (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Executive Order 9066 (The Washington Post, 1972, June 27), 1972-1973. (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Protest on Green Beret case (The New York Times, 1969, August 7), 1965-1972. (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - How a President is chosen. (U.S. News & World Report, 1972), 1970-1977.; Includes maps, Kabuki, Euthanasia, etc. (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Alphabetical list of American correspondents, 1971, January.; Includes a list of Japanese poets, writers, journalists, and libraries sent Sakai shishus. (Box 70, Folder 8)
- Publications, Not By Sakai, Indexed by author/entry.
  - American Historical Association. What shall be done about Japan after victory?, 1945. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Asahi kyuyukai. Kaiin meibo, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Bannai, Tomio. ECC Dokuhon. vol.1, 1962.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bannai, Tomio. EEC Dokuhon. vol.2, 1962.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Congress. Senate. Committee on Foreign Relations. Background information relating to Southeast Asia and Vietnam, 1970. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Department of State. Soviet Note on Berlin: an analysis, 1959. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fujimura, Tsukuru[?] ed. Saikaku Zenshu vol.2, 1930. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Furugaki, Tetsuro. Kokoro nikuki hitobito, 1966.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Furugaki, Tetsuro. Kotetsugyo no uta, 1965.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Furugaki, Tetsuro. Kokoro ni kizamareta hitobito, 1968.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Furugaki, Tetsuro. Kokoro ni ikiru hitobito, 1973.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hakubunkan hensankyoku. Ninjobon kessakushu vol.2, 1909 (c1895). (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Harako, Rinjiro; Bannai, Tomio, jt. ed., 1961.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hatta, Motoo. Miyoshi Juro oboegaki, 1969. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hiraga, Kamesuke[?] Ippon no kugi, 1970.; Editor: Sakai Yoneo. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Ichimura, Kiyoshi. Tokon hitosuji ni, 1964.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Inaba, Hidezo. Gekido 30nen no Nihon keizai, 1965.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Irie, Akira. Beichu kankei, 1971.; Inscribed. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ishibashi, Shojiro. Watashi no ayumi, 1962[?].; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ishibashi, Shojiro. Kaisoki, 1970.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ito, Shinkichi. Shi no furusato, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Iwanami shoten. Sagaken: Iwanami shashin bunko 267, 1958. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Kamiyama, Sojin. Sugao no hariuddo, 1930.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Kato, Shunpei. Kami naki shukyo, Zen, 1956.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kiba, Hirosuke, ed. Nomura Kichizaburo, 1961.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kitahara, Hakushu. Hakushu shohin, 1919. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Koide, Joe. Aru zaibei Nihonjin no kiroku. vol.1, 1967.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Kotsuji, Seiyu. Yudaya minzoku, 1968 (c. 1965).; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kuickerbarker, Diedrich. A history of New York, 1848. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mita, Heihachi. Shishu Ashiato, 1936.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Hada no nioi, 1950.; Inscribed. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Haikyo, 1948 (c. 1947).; Inscribed. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Miyoshi Juro sakuhinshu. vol.1, 1952. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Miyoshi Juro sakuhinshu. vol.2, 1952. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Miyoshi Juro sakuhinshu. vol.3, 1952. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Miyoshi Juro sakuhinshu. vol.4, 1952. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Sono hito o shirazu, 1948.; Inscribed. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Gake, 1948.; Inscribed. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miyoshi, Juro. Kyofu no kisetsu, 1950.; Inscribed. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mongolian Buddhists' Association. Gandantehchinling, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nagasugi, Kisuke. Shimomura Kojin den, 1970. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Nagasugi, Kisuke; Nagasugi, Kiyoko. Oya no tachiba ko no tachiba, 1964 (c. 1963).; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nagasugi, Kisuke, ed. Ishi ariki, 1967.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Nagasugi, Yoshisuke. Ikiru to iukoto, 1967. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Nanye, Jiro. Shishu, Ao no rekishi, 1965.; Inscribed. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Oka, Shigeki. Ii tairo, 1948.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Otake, Masato. Shosetsu, Watashino Miyoshi Juro den, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Otsuka, Takeshi. Kyuta no kumiaikan, 1932. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Oya, Soichi. Sekai no urakaido o yuku, 1955.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Oyama, Kunio. Nihon no shinro, 1948.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sakai, Seiichi. Puroretaria kashu, 1931. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Sato, Kanzan. Nihon meito monogatari, 1962.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shimomura, Kojin. Kono hito o miyo, 1966.; 1 items.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Shin kyodo. vol.7 no.7., 1954. (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Sochudo[?] Sochudo hanbai shomoku[?], 1963.; Inscribed. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Suzuki, Taisetsu. Taiwa, Ningen ikani ikubekika, 1967. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Tairen nihonjin hikiage taisaku kyogikai. Genki de iko, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Takahashi, Aiko. Kaisen kara no nikki, 1955.; Inscribed. no.362 of the limited edition of 500 copies. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Takahashi, Shinkichi. Bijutsu ronshu, Suzume 6, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Takami, Jun. Shishu, Waga maiso, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Takehisa, Yumeji. Ren'ai hiwa, 1924. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Tonogaoka, Priory. Seikai tenrei, 1937.; Inscribed. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Tsunoda, Fusako. Amazon no uta, 1967 (c. 1966).; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Government. Arms control achievements 1959-1972: U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency publication 63, Second edition (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Whittemore, Edward P. Sandai shimbun hihan / ... Translated by Irie Michimasa, 1962.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yamakawa, Hitoshi; Takahashi, Masao, et. al. Nihon no kakumei o kataru, 1948.; Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Yamamoto, Sanehiko. Sekai bunkajin junrei, 1948.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yoneda, Karl G. Zaibei Nihonjin rodosha no rekishi, 1967.; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Diaries [Restricted]
  - 1951-1955. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1960-1966. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1964. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1960-1965. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 1965-1967. (Box 25)
  - 1967-1974. (Box 26)
  - 1961-1965. (Box 31)
  - 1961-1965. (Box 32)
  - 1969-1977. (Box 34)
  - 1962-1963. (Box 40)
  - 1962-1963. (Box 41)
  - 1962-1963. (Box 42)
  - 1961-1965. (Box 43)
  - 1962-1963. (Box 44)
  - 1961-1975. (Box 46)
  - 1955-1969., Large sketchbooks. (Box 47)
  - 1955-1958. (Box 48)
  - 1962-1964. (Box 49)
  - 1960-1964. (Box 50)
  - 1955-1958. (Box 51)
  - 1961-1962. (Box 52)
  - 1958-1960. (Box 53)
  - 1958-1961. (Box 54)
  - 1957-1961. (Box 55)
  - 1958-1960. (Box 56)
  - 1959-1961. (Box 57)
  - 1960-1961. (Box 58)
  - 1959-1961. (Box 59)
  - 1960-1961. (Box 60)
  - 1965-1972., 6 items. (Box 68, Folder 2)
- Manuscripts, Primarily Unpublished [Restricted]
  - 1965-1972. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1969-1971. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1965-1972. (Box 16)
  - 1966-1975. (Box 17)
  - 1954-1971. (Box 18)
  - 1951-1972. (Box 19)
  - 1966-1969. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1969-1973. (Box 68, Folder 1)